Arnold Choy Senior Full Stack Developer

- arnold.choy93@outlook.com
- Vancouver, Canada
- https://arnoldchoy.netlify.app

in www.linkedin.com/in/arnold-choy

www.github.com/potentialdev-web

EXPERIENCE

Senior Full Stack Developer

FortunesTech 1 6 1

04/2023 - 06/2023 | Romote, Contract

- Worked directly with customers, serving as the help desk for them but also helping collect their business needs.
- Improved on-site SEO of commercial clients' websites.
- Queried and mutated information from the back-end using GraphQL with React Apollo.
- Maintained stability with E2E tests, unit tests, global error reporting, and continuous integration.

Senior Frontend Engineer

Jobscan

05/2020 - 02/2023 | Remote, Full-time

- Served primarily as a front-end engineer and did some full-stack work.
- Oversaw the MVP and beta launch, the product becoming profitable.
- Built a web extension for Chrome and Firefox—allowing users to collect, track and manage job applications from across the web.
- Refactored tests and implementation code throughout the codebase.

Senior Frontend Engineer

Cru

07/2019 - 02/2020 | Remote, Contract

- Worked with a team of developers to migrate the existing UI from AngularJS to React, add an extensive list of new features, and add unit tests and component tests for all features, key users, and roles.
- Integrated a third-party identity service, Okta, and related UI flows, including account activation, login, forgot password, and session management using JWT, token validation, and session cookies.
- Helped improve GraphQL schema for consumption by Apollo Client.
- Revamped the entire components and pages with new Figma designs.

Senior Full Stack Developer

Flux

06/2018 - 04/2019 | Remote, Contract

- Led the end-to-end development process, including database design, front-end and back-end development, and AWS deployment, utilizing Node, React, and MongoDB as the tech stack.
- Overcame the challenge of limited payment integration options in Malaysia by conducting extensive research and selecting the best available service, Molpay, despite its limitations.
- Developed the Minimum Viable Product (MVP) within a tight timeframe of just 6
 months, ensuring its successful adoption by customers who are now actively utilizing
 the platform's car and motorcycle lending services.

Senior Full Stack Developer

DroneBlocks

02/2017 - 02/2018 | Remote, Contract

 Spearheaded the development of a cutting-edge drag-and-drop editor using Google's Blockly library for the innovative DroneBlocks.io platform.

SUMMARY

Arnold is a senior software engineer with 9 years of experience and is keen on working with a diverse set of technologies and programming languages, specializing in JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Vue, Node, Ruby and GraphQL, as the most used languages in the front-end and back-end development projects he got involved in.

He places a high priority on customer satisfaction, is easy to work with, and is comfortable in agile environments. An avid learner, a great communicator, and an excellent addition to teams of all sizes.

SKILL

Client-side

React, Vue.js, Next.js, Material UI, Tailwind, Ant Design

Server-side

Node.js, Express.js, Ruby, TypeScript, GraphQL, RestfulAPI

Databases

MySQL, PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch, MongoDB, Redis, DynamoDB

DevOps

CI/CD, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Azure, AWS, Google Cloud Platform

VOLUNTEERING

Senior Full Stack Developer

AllClear

03/2020 - 05/2020

AllClear is an open-source project for helping to fight COVID19 by providing the fastest way to find a nearby test center.

 Worked as a senior full stack developer and a member of 30 person volunteers, committed to an open-source project for helping to fight COVID19.

FREELANCING

Freelance Full Stack Developer

Toptal

03/2015 - 09/2018

- Successfully customized the editor to suit the specific needs of drone control, seamlessly transforming generated code blocks into executable commands for the Tello drone.
- Overcame complex challenges related to exception handling and troubleshooting issues within the Blockly library, demonstrating exceptional problem-solving skills and ensuring the smooth functioning of the platform.

Full Stack Developer

Moorhouse Coating

06/2016 - 12/2016 | Remote, Contract

- Served as a lead developer for building a complex project for managing painting proposals with POS, scheduling, task management, work orders, invoicing, and payment system.
- Focused on building front-end heavily in user interface development and in customizing websites to be easy to update and use.
- Worked on managing the Git workflow, reviewing the tasks completed and code.
- Built RESTful and functional APIs that run effectively on Node.js and use a connected PostgreSQL database.

UI Engineer

WorkBoard

05/2015 - 04/2016 | Remote, Contract

- Built user interface, kanban board, data visualizations, and designed overall user experience, resulting in a 20% increase in users.
- Wrote high-quality code covered with the unit and e2e tests using Jest and Enzyme.
- Implemented UI for visualization Nested Sets structure of documents display in a drag & drop file structure, files and folders view, creation, deleting, and editing.
- Supported the CTO with various management tasks as high-level architectural decisions.

Full Stack Developer

Taskade

09/2012 - 03/2015 | Remote, Full-time

- Built a feature to integrate all scheduled tasks and projects in the user calendar with our one-way syncing with API Token and wrote the instructions.
- Engineered a Node.js/Express server, utilizing routing and middleware capabilities to make request calls to a SQL database.
- Engineered an automated deployment strategy by integrating Mocha/Chai, Travis CI, Docker, and AWS EC2.
- Built front-end using React Hooks with Redux and Sass for styling.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Science

University of Toronto
08/2008 - 08/2012 | Toronto, Canada